>>So we had a lot of great questions
在论坛上关于哈希表
about hash tables on the forums
我们有很多很棒的问题
and one example is Student Baracha asks
一个例子是学生 Baracha 提问：
"How does Python decide how many buckets
"Python 如何决定当字典成长变大时
a dictionary has as it grows?"
要有多少“桶” (bucket) 呢?"
>>So this is an important question, and
这是一个重要的问题
there are lots and lots of interesting things about hash tables
关于哈希表还有很多、很多有趣的事情
that we did not get into in Unit 5.
但在第五单元我们没有谈到
If memory was free and cheap, and equally fast
如果内存是免费、廉价、而且同样地快速
no matter how much you needed,
无论你需要多少
then you'd want the hash table to be as big as possible, right?
你宁愿哈希表越大越好 对吗?
You'd want billions of buckets in your hash tables
你会想要你的哈希表里有数十亿个“桶”
so they'd never have to have more than one entry in a bucket.
然后在每个“桶”内 就不必储存一个以上的项目
But as we saw in Unit 3, memory can be expensive.
但正如我们在第三单元所见 内存可能很昂贵
And the faster and the closer to the processor the memory is,
速度愈快而且愈接近处理器的内存
the more expensive it is.
它的费用也愈昂贵
So you have a very limited amount of that,
所以你的内存数量非常有限
there's a reason to try to keep the hash tables small as well.
这是尽量保持哈希表小的原因
So this is a tough trade-off.
这是一个艰难的权衡
Good hash table implementations
好的哈希表实作
try to make this trade-off in a way that gives you the right balance
尝试为你做了权衡
of performance and memory use.
让你在性能和内存使用上 得到适当的平衡
They do this by looking at the load factor.
他们根据负载因数 (load factor) 来做权衡
We actually used this in Unit 4.
我们确实在第四单元使用它
This is just the number of entries divided by the number of buckets.
也就是“项目的数量”除以“桶数”
We had that question in Unit 5. The question where it was "N divided by B"
我们在第五单元有一个问题 “N 除以 B”
where you're looking at the impact of the change of the number of buckets and the number of entries.
在问题中 你看到“桶数”和“项目的数量”变化所产生的影响
One thing you have to worry about when you do that
当你做这件事时 你必须担心一件事
is if you're just looking at the number of keywords and the number of buckets,
如果你只看着“关键字数目”和“桶数”
that's the average size. What matters in many applications
这是平均的大小 但在许多应用中的问题
is more the worst size. Even if the average size is fairly small,
更重要的是“最坏的大小” 即使平均大小是相当小的
the worst size could be much larger than that,
“最坏的大小”可能会比这个大得多
and if the lookup for the worst case entry
如果对于最坏情况的项目做查找开始变得很糟
starts to get very bad, then you want a larger number of buckets
然后你会想要更多的“桶”
or to change your hash function in some way.
或是以某种方式来改变你的 hash 函数
So, for a typical hash table implementation,
所以 对于一个典型的哈希表实作
the goal is to keep the load factor actually below 1 usually.
通常目标是要让负载因数实际上小于 1
For Python's dictionary implementation,
对于 Python 的字典实作
if the number of keywords exceeds about 2/3,
如果关键字的数量超过约 2/3
and I think it's actually exactly 2/3 of the size of the table,
我认为它实际上刚好是表的大小的 2/3
that's the point where the table is resized.
这是表的大小重新做调整的点
So the table would then be doubled, and that changes
表会变成两倍大
the bucket each word would appear in,
这会改变每个字所出现的“桶”
because we saw that the result of the hash function
因为我们之前看到哈希表的结果
depends on the number of buckets you have.
取决于你所拥有的“桶数”
So you'd have to copy things into the new hash table
因此必须要将资料复制到新的哈希表
that has more space, but that's going to make the look-ups faster.
新的哈希表有更多的空间 会使得查找速度更快
So this means that if you had about a million entries in your hash table,
也就是说 如果你在哈希表有大约 100 万个项目
you would expect to have about a million and a half buckets.
你会期待有 150 万个“桶”
But as you increase above that 2/3 threshold,
但当你增加到 2/3 的门槛值
then you'd double the size of the buckets.
然后你要把“桶”的大小增为两倍
So you'd end up with 3 million buckets,
所以你最后会有 300 万“桶”
if you added one more entry beyond that.
如果你在 2/3 的门槛值上多加一个项目
So if you compare this to what we did in Unit 5,
所以 如果你比较这个与我们在第五单元所做的
you might be surprised that it's so low.
你可能会惊讶它的负载因数是如此之低
We were doing example hash tables,
我们做的哈希表范例
where the number of buckets was very small,
“桶数”非常小
and each bucket had many entries in it.
每“桶”有许多项目
This is partly to be easier to see what's going on,
这部分是为了更容易看出到底是怎么回事
because if you saw a hash table with thousands of
因为如果你看到一个哈希表有上千个空“桶”
empty buckets, that would be kind of hard to print out.
那将很难列印出来
But the other reason for that is the way we implemented
但其他的原因是
the hash table in Unit 5 was each bucket was a list.
我们在第五单元实作哈希表的方式是每个“桶”是一个列表
And with a list, that's a fairly expensive data structure.
使用列表 这是一种相当昂贵的资料结构
You've got to create all those empty lists to
你得建立这些空列表
create your hash table.
才能建立你的哈希表
The way the Python dictionary is implemented,
Python 字典的实作方式
there's just one flat list.
只是一个扁平的列表
That means there's one space for each
这意谓着每个 hash 值只有一个空间
hash value, that if you hashed to a given bucket
如果 hash 到一个特定的“桶”
there's only one space there.
只存在一个空间
That means if two things hash to the same bucket,
也就是说 如果两个物件 hash 到相同的“桶”
you've got to do something else.
你必须去做点别的事情
And what happens with the Python dictionary implementation
Python 字典实作如何处理呢
is you look for another free place to put it
你需要另一个多余的地方来放置它
and you have a way for deciding where you look for the next one
你有方法来决定当第一个“桶”满了时
if the first one is full.
到那里寻找下一个
This makes look-ups and adding to the table more complicated,
这使得查找和添加项目到表中 变得更为复杂
so that's why we didn't do it.
这就是为什么我们没有这样做的原因
But it means you're using less memory,
但这也意谓着 使用较少的内存
because you don't have all those empty lists
因为你不必为这些'空桶'
for all the empty buckets.
存放这些空列表
There's a great chapter in a book called "Beautiful Code"
"Beautiful Code" 这本书中有一章很棒
that's all about the Python dictionary implementation.
谈的是所有关于 Python 字典的实作
So if you're interested in how that's actually done,
所以 如果你对实际的实作感到兴趣
I encourage you to look at that chapter.
我鼓励你看看这一章